Partial Guide to the Memorial Library of Music Collection
Department of Special Collections
- 1792-1793. Thérèse. / MASSENET, JULES EMILE FREDERIC (1842-1912), MLM 707
  Drame musical en deux actes de Jules Claretie. Musique de J. Massenet. Partition chant et piano. Paris, Heugel, c1907. Pl. no. H. & Cie. 22,792. First edition. Inscribed: ""A Henri Albers à l'ami, à l'artiste que j'aime et que j'admire. J. Massenet. Paris, mai 1911,"" also inscribed to Albers by Claretie and signed by composer and librettist on half-title.
- Toccata pour piano par J. Massenet. / MASSENET, JULES EMILE FREDERIC (1842-1912), MLM 708
  Paris, Heugel [1896] Pl. no. H. & Cie. 9264. First edition. Inscribed to Mme. de Silva by the composer.
- La vierge. / MASSENET, JULES EMILE FREDERIC (1842-1912), MLM 709
  Légende sacrée en quatre scènes de Ch. Grandmongin. Musique de J. Massenet. Paris, G. Hartmann [1880] Pl. no. G. H. 1093. First edition. Inscribed to Gounod by the composer. The inscription includes nine bars from the score with accompanying text. Wotquenne, 1175.
- Werther. / MASSENET, JULES EMILE FREDERIC (1842-1912), MLM 710
  Drame lyrique en trois actes et quatre tableaux d'après Goethe. Poème de MM. Edouard Blau, Paul Milliet et Georges Hartmann. Musique de J. Massenet. Partition chant et piano. Paris, Heugel [1892] First edition. Pl. no. G. H. et Cie. 1812. Inscribed to Mme. Mathieu by the composer. The inscription includes three bars from the score. Presented for the first time at Vienna, February 16, 1892. Wotquenne, 2942. See also Lalo, Victor Antoine Edouard (1823-1892) Fiesque, divertissement.